Guide to the Hartt School phonograph records ARCH138
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Hartt School phonograph records
1938-1986, undated
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
Hartt School
Paranov, Moshe, 1895-1994
ARCH138
5.65 Linear Feet (19 containers)
The Hartt School phonograph records is a collection of phonograph records collected by the Hartt School which pertain to the school and its students, faculty, and alumni.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to all researchers.
Scope and Contents
The Hartt School phonograph records consists of phonograph recordings which feature Hartt School students, faculty, and alumni as performers, conductors, and/or composers in recordings from 1938-1986. The collection was initially started by Moshe Paranov, and has been added to over the years. Recordings include Hartt ensembles, albums featuring Hartt faculty and alumni, as well as radio, festival, and other live recorded performances. The live recorded events oftentimes feature Moshe Paranov as the conductor and are frequently for non-Hartt School ensembles. Some recordings in the collection were accompanied with materials such as programs, newspaper clippings, correspondence, performer information, and other ephemera.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series: I. Phonograph Records, II. Ephemera, and III. Duplicates.
Sound recordings; Phonograph records; Record covers; Hartt College of Music -- Alumni and Alumnae; Hartt School -- Faculty; Hartt School; Hartt College of Music; Hartt Opera-Theater Guild; Hartt School. Community Division; WTIC (Radio station: Hartford, Conn.)
- Phonograph Recordings, 1938-1986, undated
  Scope and Contents
  The Phonograph Recordings series, makes up the majority of the collection and consists of various phonograph records retained by the Hartt School. These recorded performances are often either performed, conducted, and/or composed by Hartt faculty, students, and alumni. However, in some rare cases, no known relationship exists between the performers, conductors, or composers and the Hartt School. This series includes the original record covers (when available), but does not include ephemera that was found with some of the recordings. These items are located in the Ephemera series.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged into four subseries by disc size: a) 7-inch and 8-inch Phonograph Recordings, b) 10-inch Phonograph Recordings, c) 12-inch Phonograph Recordings, and d) 16-inch Transcription Discs.
  - 7-inch and 8-inch Phonograph Records, 1952-1956, undated
    - California State College at Long Beach and State University College at Fredonia, New York Clarinet Choirs, undated; 1 Phonographs 7in. (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 1.1)
      Phonograph record from the Kendor Ensemble Series released by Kendor Music, Inc. (35443). Side one features the California State College at Long Beach Clarinet Choir, conducted by Charles D. Yates performing Untitled Poem by John Rarig. Side two features the State University College at Fredonia, New York Clarinet Choir, conducted by William C. Willett (Hartt faculty) performing Clarinetics by Klauss.
    - Folk Music Lecture, 1956 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 1.2)
    - Mannes School Orchestra; Gagliarda, 1952 May 28; 1 Phonographs 8in. (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 1.3)
      Phonograph record of the Mannes School Orchestra, conducted by Carl Bamberger, performing Gagliarda by Alvin L. Epstein (Hartt faculty) on May 28, 1952.
    - Unidentified [W. Willet?], undated (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 2)
  - 10-inch Phonograph Records, 1947-1955, undated
    - Arnold Franchetti, Game of Cards, undated (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 3)
    - Hartt Symphony Orchestra, Spring Choral Festival, 1955 Apr 24 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 4)
    - Mollen Hauer, Fantasia, 1947 May 29 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 5)
    - Irene Kahn and Moshe Paranov (Dual Pianists), Chess Seranade, undated (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 6)
    - Suzanne Kirby, performed by Earl Rogers and Annabel Briett, 1955 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 7)
    - Massachusetts All-State Orchestra, 1951 Feb 17 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 8)
    - Ted Melyan, Bagatelle, undated (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 9)
    - Ted Melyan, Soliloquy, undated (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 10-11)
    - New York Sectional Orchestra, 1953 Nov 21 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 12)
    - NYSSMA All-State Orchestra, 1951 Nov 17 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 13)
    - NYSSMA All-State Orchestra, 1953 Dec 5 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 14)
    - Putche, undated (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 15-16)
    - Rieding, First Movt. Concerto, 1947 May 29 (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 17)
    - Freidrich Schorr; Shumann Liederkreis, Opus 39, undated (Box 10in. Phonograph Records, Folder 18-25)
  - 12-inch Phonograph Records, 1938-1986, undated
    The series is arranged alphabetically by the last name of the primary performer, or when appropriate by the primary ensemble or event name.
    - All-Connecticut Music Festival, 1968 Oct 25; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1)
      Phonographs record of the All-Connecticut Music Festival on October 25, 1968 featuring orchestra, chorus, and band (with orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov).
    - All-Maryland High School Orchestra and Chorus, 1972 Oct 20; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1)
      One phonograph record of the All-Maryland High School Orchestra (guest conducted by Moshe Paranov) and Chorus on October 20, 1972.
    - All-Suffolk Junior High School Orchestra and Chorus, 1958; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1, Box Record Covers 1)
      Two phonograph records of the 1958 All-Suffolk Junior High School Orchestra and Chorus (orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov).
    - American Festival of Music, 1958 Feb 15; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1)
      Phonograph record of the 1958 American Festival of Music performance of Suite for Piano by Jeremy Joyce Laverne, performed by Marcia Heller.
    - Harold Bauer; Harold Bauer Plays Chopin, 1970; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1)
      One phonograph record of the album Harold Bauer plays Chopin featuring Harold Bauer, released by Klavier Record Company (KS-113).
    - Harold Bauer; Johannes Brahms, Sonata in F Minor, Op. 5, undated; 4 Phonographs With record cover book 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1, Box Record Covers 1)
      Four phonograph records of Harold Bauer performing Sonata in F Minor, Op. 5 by Johannes Brahms. Record by Schirmer's Library of Recorded Music, Set No. 14.
    - Harold Bauer; Moonlight Sonata and Gavotte in F Major, undated; 2 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1)
      Two phonograph records of Harold Bauer performing Moonlight Sonata and Gavotte in F Major by Ludwig van Beethoven. Recording by RCA Victor Company (6591-A/B and 6592-A/B).
    - Harold Bauer; Schumann, Fantasiestucke (Opus 12), Circa 1941; 4 Phonographs With record cover book 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1, Box Record Covers 1)
      Four phonograph records of Harold Bauer performing Robert Schumann's Fantasiestucke (Opus 12).Recording by RCA Victor Company (14487-A/B through 14489-A/B).
    - Harold Bauer and Alfred Cohen, 1940 Nov 24; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 1)
      Phonograph record of Harold Bauer and Alfred Cohen performing Flourish and Ye Sweet Retreat, recorded by WTIC.
    - Melvin Berman with Kelsey Jones and Walter Joachim; Vivaldi, Il Pastor Fido - Six Sonatas Op. 13 for Oboe and Continuo, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of Vivaldi's Il Pastor Fido - Six Sonatas Op. 13 for Oboe and Continuo performed by Melvin Berman with Kelsey Jones and Walter Joachim. Recorded in Church of St. John the Evangelist, Montreal. Released by Everest Records Production (2875).
    - Ernest Bloch; Sacred Service (Avodath Hakodesh), 1949; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of Ernest Bloch conducting his piece Sacred Service (Avodath Hakodesh) performed by Marko Rothmuller, Dorothy Bond, Doris Cowan with the London Philharmonic Choir and London Philharmonic Orchestra. Released by the London Gramophone Corporation (London Record, LLP 123).
    - Brockton [Orchestral Society?]; Farm Journal, undated; 2 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Two phonograph records of what is believed to be the Brockton Orchestral Society, performing Farm Journal.
    - Brockton Orchestral Society; Stars and Stripes Forever, undated; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of the Brockton Orchestral Society, performing Stars and Stripes Forever by John Philip Sousa.
    - Marçal Cervera and Rafael Puyana; Johann Sebastian Bach: 3 Sonaten Für Viola de Gamba & Cembalo, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of the album Johann Sebastian Bach: 3 Sonaten Für Viola de Gamba & Cembalo released by Philips (9502 003), featuring Marçal Cervera and Rafael Puyana (Hartt alumnus).
    - Vincent Coffin; Juke Box Jingles, 1952 Feb 1; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record labelled as "VIP disc. Vincent Coffin, chairman of the 1952 drive, Juke Box Jingles." It is unclear what Vincent Coffin's role in the recording, if any. It is also not clear how this recording relates to the recording "Moshe Paranov, Juke Box Jingles, 1952 Feb 8." Both recordings were made by WTIC.
    - Connecticut All-State Band, 1954 Oct 28; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of the Connecticut All-State Band on October 28, 1954.
    - The Contemporary Chamber Players of the University of Chicago, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph records of the Contemporary Chamber Players of the University of Chicago, conducted by Ralph Shapey, performing The Cat and the Moon by Thomas Putsché (Hartt faculty), Requiems for the Party-Girl by R. Murray Schafer, and Cantus Commemorabilias I by Henry Weinberg. Album released by Composers Recordings (CRI SD 245) in 1969.
    - Mario Davidovsky and Barbara Kolb, 1972; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of Synchronisms No. 6, Electronic Study No. 3, and Synchronisms No. 5 composed by Mario Davidovsky, and Trobar Clus and Solitaire for Piano and Vibes composed by Barbara Kolb (Hartt alumnae). Albulm released by Turnabout Vox (TV-S 34487).
    - Luiz De Moura Castro; Schumann, Liszt, Ginastera, and de Falla, 1984 Oct 2; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of extracts of Luiz de Moura Castro's performance of Arabesque, Opus 18 (Schumann), Sonata in B Minor (Liszt), Suite de Danzas Criollas (Ginastera), and Ritual Fire Dance (from El Amor Brujo) (de Falla) on October 2, 1984 at Merkin Concert Hall, Abraham Goodman House. Album released by Educo Records (3157).
    - Luiz De Moura Castro; Villa-Lobos and Liszt, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of Luiz de Moura Castro performing Lenda Do Coboclo, Choros No. 5, Aria from Bachianas Brasileiras No. 4, Impressoes Seresteiras, Dansa Do Indio Branco by Heitor Villa-Lobos and Ave Maria, St. Francis of Paola Walking on the Waters, Funerailles by Franz Liszt. Album released by Educo Records (3118).
    - Alfred Drake, Roberta Peters; Carousel, with Claramae Turner, Lee Venora, Norman Treigle, and Jon Crain, 1962; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of the album Carousel featuring Alfred Drake and Roberta Peters, with Claramae Turner, Lee Venora (Hartt alumnae), Norman Treigle, and Jon Crain. Album released by Grand Award Record Company (RS 843 SD).
    - Eastern Division Connecticut Music Educators' Association Concert Festival, 1965 Jan 30; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of the Third Eastern Division Connecticut Music Educators' Association Concert Festival at Jorgenson Auditorium at the University of Connecticut on January 30, 1965. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Eastern Division Connecticut Music Educators Association Concert Festival, 1966 Jan 29; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 2)
      Phonograph record of the Fourth Eastern Division Connecticut Music Educators Association Concert Festival at the University of Connecticut on January 29, 1966. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Eastern Division Music Educators' National Conference Concert, 1967 Feb 10-13; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3, Box Record Covers 1)
      Two phonograph records of the Eastern Division Music Educators' National Conference Concert with All-Eastern High School orchestra, chorus, and band on February 10-13, 1967. The orchestra was conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Arnold Franchetti; Three Italian Masques - and Hunter Johnson; Trio for Flute, Oboe and Piano, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      Phonograph record of Arnold Franchetti's Three Italian Masques: Concertino for Piano, Brass, Percussion and Bass featuring Raymond Hanson (piano, Hartt faculty)); the New York Brass Ensemble; Robert Nagel, John Glasel, and Ted Weis (trumpets); Keith Brown and David Uber (trombones); Stuart Sankey (bass); Ronald Gould (percussion); and Samuel Baron (conductor). Record also includes Hunter Johnson's Trio for Flute, Oboe and Piano with Julius Baker (flute), Robert Bloom (oboe), and Douglas Nordli (piano). Album released by Composers Recordings, Inc. (CRI-125).
    - Alfred C. Fuller; Address to the Rotary Club of Los Angeles, 1949 Feb 18; 3 Phonographs With record cover book 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3, Box Record Covers 1)
      Three phonograph records of an address by Alfred C. Fuller to the Rotary Club of Los Angeles, California at the Biltmore Hotel.
    - Raya Garbousova; Cello Melodies, undated; 3 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3, Box Record Covers 1)
      Three phonograph records of the album Cello Melodies performed by Raya Garbousova. Album released by RCA Victor Company (11-8869-A/B through 11-8871-A/B).
    - Leopold Godowsky; Columbia Record Symphony Series, undated; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      Phonograph record of Leopold Godowsky (piano) performing Gondoliera in G Flat, and If I Were a Bird Op.2, No. 6 by Hanselt, as well as Waltz by Chopin. Album released by Columbia Graphophone Company (A5791).
    - Caren Goodin and Stephen Glover, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      One phonograph record released by the International Piano Library (IPL 1001) featuring Caren Goodin (Hartt alumnae) performing Moszkowski's Piano Concerto with a symphony orchestra and Stephen Glover performing Godowsky's Passacaglia.
    - Hartt College of Music Chamber and Madrigal Singers; MENC Eastern Division Concert, 1969 Jan 30; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      Phonograph record of the Hartt College of Music Chamber and Madrigal Singers performing at the MENC Eastern Division Concert in Washington, D.C. on January 30, 1969. Directed by Gerald Mack with organist Richard Matteson.
    - Hartt College of Music Summer Youth Music Program Concert, 1968; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      Phonograph record of the Hartt College of Music Summer Youth Music Program Concert in 1968. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov, chorus conducted by Gerald Mack, and band conducted by Donald Mattran.
    - Hartt College of Music Summer Youth Concert, 1971; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      Two phonograph records of the Hartt College of Music Summer Youth Concert in 1971. Conducted by Moshe Paranov, Gerald Mack, Donald Mattran, and William Willett, with guest members William Elwell and Janice Gibeau.
    - Hartt College of Music Summer Youth Concert, 1972; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      Two phonograph records of the Hartt College of Music Summer Youth Music Program Concert in 1972. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov, chorus conducted by Gerald Mack, and band conducted by Donald Mattran.
    - Hartt College of Music Summer Youth Concert, Record 2, 1974; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      Phonograph record of the Hartt College of Music Summer Youth Music Program Concert in 1974. The phonograph is labelled as Record Two and only contains recordings of the Orchestra, the Archives does not have Record One. The orchestra was conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Hartt College Symphony Orchestra; MENC Eastern Division Concert, 1969; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 3)
      Phonograph record of the Hartt College Symphony Orchestra at the MENC Eastern Division Concert at Washington, D.C. in 1969. Conducted by Nathan Gottschalk, the concert includes performances of Roman Carnival Overture by Hector Berlioz, Sinfonietta for String Orchestra, by Edward Miller (Hartt Faculty), and Symphonic Metamorphosis of Themes by Carl Maria Von Weber by Paul Hindemith.
    - Hartt Opera Guild?; Hansel and Gretel, undated; 1 Phonographs Lacquer disc with fiberboard core 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4)
      Phonograph record of an opera production of Hansel and Gretel most likely performed by the Hartt Opera Guild.
    - Hartt Opera Guild; Marriage of the Devil, 1945 Feb 28; 5 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4)
      Five phonograph records of the Hartt Opera Guild's production of Marriage of the Devil.
    - Hartt Opera Guild; The Secret of Suzanne, 1945 Feb 28; 4 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4)
      Four phonograph records of the Hartt Opera Guild's production of The Secret of Suzanne.
    - Hartt Opera Guild; Sister Angelica, 1945 May 16; 4 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4)
      Four phonograph records of the Hartt Opera Guild's production of Sister Angelica.
    - Hartt Symphony Orchestra, 1955 Mar 27; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4)
      Phonograph record of the Hartt Symphony Orchestra on March 27, 1955.
    - Hartt Youth Symphonic Band, 1971 Feb 8; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4)
      Two phonograph records of the Hartt Youth Symphonic Band, conducted by Samuel Goldfarb, on February 8, 1971.
    - Irene Jacobi and the Coolidge Quartet; Frederick Jacobi, Hagiographa, 1938; 3 Phonographs With record cover book 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4, Box Record Covers 1)
      Three phonograph records of Frederick Jacobi's Hagiographa: Three Biblical Narratives (For String Quartet and Piano), performed by Irene Jacobi (piano) and the Coolidge Quartet, featuring William Kroll (1st violin and Hartt Faculty), Nicolai Berezowsky (2nd violin), Nicolas Moldavan (viola), and Victor Gottlieb (cello). Album released by RCA Victor (18005-S through 18007-A/B).
    - Milada Javora and Marie Bradac; Koleda: Czech and Slovak Christmas Carols, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4)
      Phonograph record of album released by Gamut Records (Hartford, CT) Koleda: Czech and Slovak Christmas Carols sung by Milada Javora (Hartt Faculty) and Marie Bradac, with organist Godfrey Tomanek.
    - Junior High School Music Festival Concert, 1973 Mar 3; 2 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4, Box Record Covers 1)
      Two phonograph records of the Nineteenth Annual Junior High School Music Festival Concert held in North Babylon, New York on March 3, 1973. Orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Gary Karr with Jeffrey Siegel; Gary Karr Plays Double Bass, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 4)
      Phonograph record of the album Gary Karr Plays Double Bass released by Golden Crest (Recital Series RE-7012), featuring Gary Karr (Hartt faculty) with Jeffrey Siegel (piano).
    - Daniel Kobialka with Myron Press; Daniel Kobialka, violinist, Plays Music of Kirchner, Cheney, Bavicchi, Circa 1963- circa 1969; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5, Box Record Covers 1)
      Phonograph record of the album Daniel Kobialka, violinist, Plays Music of Kirchner, Cheney, and Bavicchi released by Medea Records (MCLP1002), featuring Daniel Kobialka (Hartt alumnus) with Myron Press (piano).
    - Enid Katahn; Keys, Circa 1970 - circa 1979; 1 Phonographs With inscribed record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the album Keys released by Peacetree Records, featuring Enid Katahn (pianist and Hartt alumnae). The record cover includes a signed inscription from Enid to Moshe Paranov.
    - Igor Kipnis, Jay Gottlieb, and Ensemble InterContemporain; Barbara Kolb: Toccata, Appello, Soundings, 1986; 1 Phonographs With inscribed record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the album Barbara Kolb released by Composers Recordings Incorporated (CRI SD 537) in 1986, featuring three pieces composed by Barbara Kolb (Hartt alumnae): Toccata performed by Igor Kipnis (harpsichord), Appello performed by Jay Gottlieb (piano), and Soundings performed by Ensemble InterContemporain and conducted by Arturo Tamayo. The record cover includes a signed inscription from Kolb to Sam Berkman and Irene Kahn.
    - Jacob Lateiner; Brahms, undated; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the album Brahms released by Westminster Recording (XWN 18870), featuring Jacob Lateiner (piano – Hartt faculty) performing Variations and Fugue on a Theme of Handel, Op. 24 and Variations on a Theme of Paganini, Op. 35.
    - Laurel Music Camp Orchestra, 1954 Jul 2; 1 Phonographs 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the Laurel Music Camp Orchestra on July 2, 1954, conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Laurel Music Camp Concert, 1965 Jul 2; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the Laurel Music Camp performance on July 2, 1965. Chorus conducted by John Raymond, band conducted by John Corley, and orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Laurel Music Camp Concert, 1966 Jul 1; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the Laurel Music Camp performance on July 1, 1966. Chorus conducted by John Raymond, band conducted by John Corley, and orchestra conducted by Moshe Paranov.
    - Laurel Music Camp Concert, 1968 Jun 28; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the 24th Annual Laurel Music Camp Concert on June 28, 1968. Chorus conducted by Moshe Paranov, band conducted by Stanley Hettinger, and orchestra conducted by Michael Semanitsky.
    - Laurel Music Camp Concert, 1971 July 2; 1 Phonographs With record cover 12in. (Box 12in. Phonograph Records 5)
      Phonograph record of the 27th Annual Laurel Music Camp Concert on July 2, 1971. Chorus conducted by John Raymond, band conducted by Moshe Paranov, and orchestra conducted by Rouben Gregorian.